This piece right here is approximately
50,036.27
lbs of mass.
>> Approximately.
>> Approximately, yeah.
There are 20 50 50,000 lb increments in
this machine. 20 * 50 = 1 million lbs.
Cumulatively, that's 4.45 MN. These are
the largest mass objects ever
calibrated.
>> The machine works like this. Below
ground are the 20 carefully calibrated
masses. Their weight is used to
calibrate four sensors, also called
force transducers, in the lab upstairs.
>> One of these would be placed on the
compression head right here.
>> Then a hydraulic ram in the attic starts
to raise the green lifting frame. And
once the force transducer contacts the
red loading frame, well then it starts
lifting the weights downstairs. And as
the lifting [music] frame continues to
rise, more and more of the 50,000 lb
weights become suspended by the force
sensor. And since the weights create an
accurately known force, the readouts
from the force transducer [music] can be
precisely calibrated.